explorelearning.com 2019-02-12

# ExploreLearning Gizmos: Math & Science Simulations Powering Inquiry and Understanding

This site provides you with access to ExploreLearning's Data Management System. This system is an integral component of ExploreLearning's curriculum products and provides valuable reporting, instructional recommendations, and other resources used by teachers and other instructional leaders in conjunction with ExploreLearning's curriculum with the goal of improving student performance. 

This statement describes the privacy and security practices ExploreLearning employs for this site. We have adopted these practices to protect you, the students, and the school district, and to enable each of us to comply with applicable legal requirements. Use of this site requires district acceptance of the practices outlined in this statement. 

Two types of personally identifiable information are used on this site: your personal data and student data. 

ExploreLearning collects information from you as you use this site. For example, you must enter certain personally identifiable information, including your name and, for teachers, your e-mail address. We use this information to verify your identity and prevent unauthorized access to your account and to contact you in connection with your use of this site. 

In addition to the information you provide, ExploreLearning collects information about your use of this site through tracking, cookies, and log files, as described in our general [Terms of Use](https://www.explorelearning.com/index.cfm?method=Controller.dspTerms) statement. 

Because you enter your personal data, you control its accuracy. If you discover that your personal data is inaccurate or if it changes or if you want to retain possession of it, you may make corrections by notifying us at [support@ExploreLearning.com](mailto:support@ExploreLearning.com) . We will not share your personal data collected through this site with third persons without your consent. However, your personal data will be available to authorized users from your school district who have permission from the school district to access it. We will not use your personal data collected through this site for any purpose other than providing you with access to this site and the associated services. This means that we will not use your data to display contextual or behavioral advertising, will not use the data to track and target advertisements on third party websites, and will not allow third parties to use your data to create ad profiles, perform data enhancement or target ads. We will use the same security to protect your personal data that we use to protect student data collected through this site. We may use anonymized data collected through your use of ExploreLearning products to enhance those products. 

As you use this site, you will enter student data or interact with student data that has already been entered. Under the terms of our contracts with schools, we agree to act as a "School Official" as defined by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act ("FERPA"), meaning that we: 

  * Perform an institutional service or function for which the school or district would otherwise use its own employees;
  * Have been determined to meet the criteria set forth in the school's or district's annual notification of FERPA rights for being a School Official with a legitimate educational interest in the education records;
  * Are under the direct control of the school or district with regard to the use and maintenance of education records; and
  * Use education records only for authorized purposes and will not re-disclose from education records to other parties (unless we have specific authorization from the school or district to do so and it is otherwise permitted by FERPA)

However, FERPA requires limitations on disclosure of those records and implementation of appropriate security measures to protect those records. To help your school district comply with FERPA, ExploreLearning has adopted certain practices, and requires that educators using this site fulfill certain responsibilities to safeguard student data. Additionally, ExploreLearning operates in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"). ExploreLearning will not knowingly collect or use personally identifiable information from anyone under 13 years of age. 

The following statement explains our practices and your responsibilities regarding the student data you enter on this site. 

### Student Data Security and Confidentiality Statement

You control what student data is entered on this site and you retain ownership of the student data at all times. Student data entered on this site should be limited to information that is relevant to the legitimate educational purpose of improving student performance. We will not ask you to enter, and you are instructed not to enter, data about students that is not relevant to this legitimate educational purpose. 

Therefore, only a minimum amount of personally identifiable student data required for the setup of the system is requested. We require student first name and student last name. Additional data, not specific to the student, is also required to complete system setup, including the teacher first and last name, class name, grade level, and school name. If you choose to enter student demographic data for the purposes of optional disaggregated reporting for the Reflex product, you grant permission for ExploreLearning to host and use that data for reporting purpose. This reporting functionality is not available on Gizmos. 

#### Use, Disclosure, and Storage

We will use the student data to provide the services to your school district. We will not keep the student data after you or the school district instructs us to delete it. 

We will only disclose student data to authorized employees or representatives of the school district, and will not knowingly disclose the student data to any third person without express written authorization. When, at the request of the district, we acquire assessment or other information, including personally identifiable student data, from a third party source we treat that information with the same confidentiality and security safeguards as though it were provided directly by the district. Additional agreements may be required by the third party to authorize transmission of data to ExploreLearning. 

Your district may from time to time request that ExploreLearning provide student data to third parties of its choosing. We will do so with written authorization, which acknowledges that ExploreLearning is providing that data as your district's agent and that once the data is received by the third party, ExploreLearning no longer has any control over the use or disposition of the data. 

We may also use aggregated data in our research, product development, and marketing. That aggregated, non-personally identifiable data (e.g., summary or statistical data) may be shared with third parties. However, we do not use personally identifiable student data to market any products or services directly to students or their parents. 

In the event that ExploreLearning wishes, from time to time, to release aggregated data that identifies your school or school district by name, ExploreLearning will enter into a separate agreement with you to authorize release and publication. 

ExploreLearning does not utilize third parties to provide products and does not share your student data with any third parties. 

**We may share Personal Information with our parent company and other affiliated companies. If we enter into a business transition such as a merger, consolidation, acquisition, sale of assets, joint venture, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, liquidation, or dissolution, your Personal Information may be among the assets we transfer. You acknowledge and consent that such transfers are permitted by this Privacy Policy, and that any acquirer of ours or that acquirer's affiliates may continue to collect and use your Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.**

We use "cookies" to collect information. For example, we may use these technologies to collect information about the ways visitors use this Site - which pages they visit, which links they use, and how long they stay on each page. We also use these technologies to support certain features of this Site. For example, we use these technologies to personalize your experience when you use this Site and to save you the trouble of reentering information already in our database or to prompt the settings you established on previous visits. 

The information we collect using cookies and similar technologies is not, in and of itself, personally identifiable, but we may link it to personal information that you provide. If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer. Although you are not required to accept cookies when you visit this Site, you may be unable to use all of the functionality of this Site if your browser rejects our cookies. 

You are responsible for keeping the student data that you enter accurate, complete and up-to-date. If you recognize that student data is inaccurate, incomplete, or out-of-date, you are responsible for correcting it. If you experience problems making corrections to student data, please notify us at [support@ExploreLearning.com](mailto:support@ExploreLearning.com) and we will assist you with making corrections. 

We are committed to protecting student data against unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification or disclosure. Protecting student data requires efforts from us and from you. We will implement reasonable and appropriate safeguards when collecting student data from you and when storing that student data in our database and you will observe our security safeguards and exercise reasonable caution when using this site. 

Specific institutional and technological security safeguards include: 

  1. Only ExploreLearning employees who are authorized to handle student data are able to access the Data Management System.
  2. Only school district employees and representatives that the district authorizes as school officials are permitted to access the system. 
  3. Each authorized school official is given a Userid and Password valid for the duration of the subscription. You must safeguard your Userid and Password, and not permit any unauthorized access to student data entered or kept in ExploreLearning's system. 
  4. Upon written request by the district, ExploreLearning will destroy any student data for districts who no longer participate in an ExploreLearning program. ExploreLearning will provide written verification that the data has been destroyed as requested.
  5. 60 days following termination of a product subscription, ExploreLearning will delete the data associated with that product subscription. Upon request, ExploreLearning will provide written verification that the data has been destroyed. Notwithstanding the foregoing, anonymized usage data may be retained for internal product improvement.
  6. ExploreLearning uses industry standard server and network hardware and software to ensure that data is protected from unauthorized access or disclosure.

Although we make concerted good faith efforts to maintain the security of personal information, and we work hard to ensure the integrity and security of our systems, no practices are 100% immune, and we can't guarantee the security of information. Outages, attacks, human error, system failure, unauthorized use or other factors may compromise the security of user information at any time. If we learn of a security breach or other unauthorized disclosure of your PII, we will attempt to notify you so that you can take appropriate protective steps by posting a notice on our homepage (www.explorelearning.com and www.reflexmath.com) or elsewhere in our Service and we will send email to you at the email address you have provided to us. Additionally, we will notify the primary administrative contact at your school or district by email and telephone and assist with their efforts to ensure your notification. 

Any such notice will include:

  * The date of the breach.
  * The type of information that was subject to breach.
  * General description of what occurred.
  * Steps we are taking to address the breach.
  * The contact person with our Company who you can contact regarding the breach.

If you are a parent, legal guardian or eligible student and an unauthorized disclosure of your student's PII records occurs, we will notify you through notice to your school or district's primary administrative contact. 

When you use this site, you consent to our privacy practices and agree to accept the responsibilities outlined in this statement. 

If you have any questions, concerns or inquiries about our Privacy Policy, or our use of your PII, or our privacy practices, please contact us at [support@ExploreLearning.com](mailto:support@ExploreLearning.com) or 866-882-4141, or mail to General Counsel 17855 Dallas Parkway, Suite 400 Dallas, TX 75287. You may also contact [COPPAPrivacy@ikeepsafe.org](mailto:COPPAPrivacy@ikeepsafe.org). 

_Last Updated: November 15 th, 2018_
